Shruthi N S

Data Analyst | Teacher Mentor | Process Associate

Address Bengaluru, KA, 560099

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/shruthi96

Phone 7829533086

E-mail shruthi.ns0221@gmail.com

Adaptable Professional with 2+ years of experience with a proven knowledge in Mentoring and teaching various kids and teachers across the globe, case management, customer end support. Thriving to strengthen my skills in every opportunity and execute along with team and organization.

Skills

Data visualization and Analysis	
JavaScript , HTML , CSS , Node JS	
Data Visualization using Tableau and python	
Python3.0, Data Science for python	
User Experience , up-selling and Customer Handling	
Adaptable Team Player and Leadership traits	
Event Coordination and Management	
Computer Hardware , software support	
EDA, ML Regression models (Linear, Logistics, clustering, PCA)	

Work History

2019-11 - Current

Teacher Mentor and Online Kids Coding Expert

WhiteHat JR, Bengaluru, India, Karnataka

Coaching and mentoring initiatives

- Guiding students 1: 1 to create games using JavaScript and explaining the concepts of JavaScript in detail while creating games and applications.
- Conversation of trial classes to paid classes(Up selling).
- Mentoring the new teachers and helping them to achieve better conversion percentage and student rating.
- Achieved various milestones by completing more than 700+ classes, with 4.9 rating and 10+ conversion percentage.

2019-10 - 2019-12

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

BTL Institute Of Technology And Management, Bengaluru, India, Karnataka

 Part time guest lecture for department of Computer science and engineering to handle DBMS and Software Engineering subjects as per VTU syllabus

2019-02 - 2019-08 **SENIOR ASSOCIATE**

Dell International Services ltd Bengaluru

- Troubleshooting the hardware components of the end users and up-selling the dell products.
- Responsible in providing the basic software support and complete hardware support for desktops, laptops, printers and docking stations and to find out the faulty components, quote them accordingly.
- Responsible to create case, owning the case until the issue is resolved.

2017-11 - 2019-02 **PROCESS ASSOCIATE**

Tek Systems, Hewlett Packard, Bengaluru, India, Karnataka

- Worked on Hyper-converged device called Simplivity.
- Working on SFDC tickets and creating new tickets as per the notification alarms generated by a simplivity tool.
- Monitoring Emails and following up the cases and alarms on daily basis.

Key Data Science Projects

Domain: BFS | Tech Stack: Python, Jupyter Notebook | Sep '20

Objective: The problem statement chosen for this project is to predict fraudulent credit card transactions with the help of machine learning models Source: Data taken from Kaggle for the analysis. Solution: Built 12 models with and without imbalance data. (Model: Logistic Regression, Random Forest, XGBoost || Balancing: Oversampling, SMOTE, ADASYN) Key Achievement: Achieved AUC of 97.41 %

Education

2019-11 - 2020-11 Post Graduation Diploma: Data Science

International Institute Of Information Technology - Bangalore

2013-08 - 2017-06 Bachelors of Engineering: Computer Science

BTL Institute Of Technology And Management - Bengaluru, Karnataka

2011-03 - 2013-03 **PUC - Science**

BCPUC

2008-06 - 2011-04 SSLC

BEML Composite PU College - Kolar, Karnataka

Certifications

2020-06 Certified Game and App Developer